J Salaski

Software Engineer

j@salaski.net (952) 212-3727 linkedin.com/in/jsalaski/ jsalaski.com

SUMMARY

Software Engineer with project management skill set; able to dissect complex problems and return efficient solutions. Experience leading teams to create, oversee, and complete initiatives using industry-standard methodologies. Looking forward to applying my experiences in a meaningful organization that is focused on community development.

EXPERIENCE

100Devs, Los Angeles, CA — Software Engineer

JANUARY 2022 - PRESENT

- Collaborate with a team of developers to build modern and responsive web applications using best practices.
- Build semantically structured full stack web applications.
- Apply project management methodologies in team-based settings.

Edina Public Schools, Edina, MN — IT Project Manager

AUGUST 2014 - PRESENT

- Responsible for management of technology initiatives: vendor management, expansion of service areas, data analysis.
- Lead the implementation of district-wide technology policies: lifecycle management, standardization of professional development, liaison with internal and external stakeholders for continual service improvement.
- Manage technology service staff and student internship programming.
- Organize, update, and present information regarding the organization's technology ecosystem.

EDUCATION

Concordia University, St. Paul, MN — Master of Business Administration

SEPT 2019 -- JULY 2021

University of Minnesota, Twin Cities, MN — B.A. in English

ENGINEERING SKILLS

HTML

CSS

JavaScript

React

React Native

Node

MongoDB

PostgreSQL

OOP

Web Accessibility

MANAGEMENT SKILLS

Project Management

Vendor Management

Data Analysis

Facilitation and Collaboration

Relationship Management

CERTIFICATIONS

Project Management Professional

ITIL Foundation